All my friends and welcome come to exercise 100 and one in this exercise, we are going to implement
that algorithm hip sort in Java.
And let's start by making its Java class inside the algorithms package, and I will call it as he saw.
So if you want to download all these source codes from the previous videos, you can download them from
their resources folder under each exercise that we have solved.
So in order to start the heap or as we have said in the previous videos, we need to make that method
hip fi.
And then we need to make the sort that calls the hip ify.
And then we need to print it, and later we will test it by the main function.
So public void and when dealing with hips.
So we need to create a method called hip before.
OK.
Into array and and and and I then find the largest among the root find here.
Largest
among adult.
Left.
And right then we create and largest equal to I.
And I'll equal to two times I +1.
And End are equal to two times, two times 30 plus two.
OK.
This is for the left and the right, not we need to start checking if al less than N..
And we are getting the largest among the roots.
So we created the entire largest.
And now we need to check which is the left or the right is greater.
And we assign the largest to it.
OK.
So if largest less than an if l less than an ant array at index
L here.
Greater then, are they at index largest, then what we make, we make largest equal to and.
If R is less than an.
And are they at index A right now that an array at index are, which is erdre right at rate at index
largest?
Then make the largest is equal to everything.
OK, is equal to rights or largest equal to or no.
We need to swap here and continue typifying if the route is not the largest.
If the road is not the largest, we will give it defying.
If large does not equal to I, so we don't we didn't reach the largest and which is not the truth.
Swab equal to array at index high.
And are they at index is equal to at the.
At.
Largest
and array and and the largest is equal to sweat.
OK.
And we keep hip defined by calling hip ify.
How do they act and expand and index blush?
OK.
This is the method that we are going to use.
This is the hip ify here.
In a recursive manner such that we check if it is the route is not thelargest, then keep it refined.
Keep refining means recursion.
OK, this is their first typify method.
OK, now let's create the method that is responsible for the sorting.
So.
Here.
Public void.
Salt and added.
It took the of the salt that we are today, that we are going to salt and we find its length so inth
and equal to our a dart length.
No build build max heap.
We start by making an array and I.
Or a loop that starts from I over two minus one
minus one and I a greater than or equal to zero and I'm minus minus what we will do, we will call the
hip if I get out of there and and I.
OK, this is what we will do in the max heap now.
The heat sort here.
Hips or.
Four in equal to N minus one I.
Greater than or equal to zero by minus minus than what we will do, we will make an entire equal to
our index zero.
And array at index zero equal to array our switching array array at index AI and array index AI now
becomes equal to them.
So we are switching these.
We are swapping these numbers by.
The index, their array at index zero becomes that right in the eye and the value of the eye equal to
at index zero.
OK, now hip ify and the root element hip ify method as they eye and we pass there, so we are switching
and hip defying these two elements.
OK, no.
We will need to print so public static void print at a faster rate that we need to print as anything
that today that we need to print and an equal rate at length and four and equal to zero by less than
an eye plus plus I.
We need to go through all the elements and pretend about them and.
Have a at and a glass of space.
OK, no system that out, that print and print a new light.
Let's make the driver code and test our.
Algorithm, this is the step take away from me, just string are x ray
and in here.
And are they equal to one?
Twenty to nine, one, 14, five, six four.
No hips or
acts as a quote to new hits her and the hips.
Now we need to call the salt method.
Andrew Pastorally, a system that allowed the complaint, Allen sought to
allay his
opponent and that index or print that a payout.
OK, so this is how we make the hips.
Let's run and see.
And our code is working fine.
We have sorted that one four, five six nine, 14 22 correctly using the hips.
OK.
And as I told you, the hips or complexity.
In all its cases, it is he actually absorbed.
I admit it.
It is all off and lug and and times
plug and
OK.
So it is analog.
This is in all the best cases, the worst cases and the average, best, worst and other
cases.
OK, so this is look and this is for the hip sort algorithm in order to to sort of pay that off.
Not.